Bharti Sharma

7/57 Sector -5, Rajender Nagar Sahibabad, Ghaziabad. UP +91-9971549107 bharti.sharma2704@gmail.com

Skills

Project Manager with 8 years of experience and a proven track record in delivering projects within the IT sector. Managing people and processes to ensure that our projects are delivered on time and produce the desired results .Always involve in project's organization and timeline management .Proficiently managing the full project lifecycle to achieve delivery on time, within budget and to the agreed quality specifications .As a Project manager my responsibilities include developing detailed project plans, ensuring resource availability and allocation and delivering every project on time within budget and scope.

SKILL SUMMARY

- Planning & Execution
- Organizing resources
- Time Management Control
- Client Management and satisfaction
- Progress Tracking
- Reports Management
- Team Handling
- Client Handling

Experience

Amicus Infotech Senior Project Coordinator

Okhla, New delhi

April 2022 to Currently working

- Plan, execute and finalize projects according to strict deadlines and within budget.
- Define project scope, goals, and deliverables in collaboration with senior management and stakeholders.
- Develop and manage project timelines & milestones.
- Coordinate and lead project meetings and ensure effective communication between team members.
- Identify project risks and develop contingency plans to mitigate those risks.
- Monitor project progress and provide regular status updates to stakeholders.
- Ensure that all project deliverables are completed on time, within budget, and to the satisfaction of stakeholders.
- Manage project documentation, including project plans, schedules, and budget reports.
- Manage project teams and resources, including assigning tasks, setting deadlines, and monitoring progress.
- Evaluate and assess project results to identify areas for improvement.

Digicorns Technologies IT *Project Manager*

Noida, UP

February 2021 to September 2021

- Coordinate internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of projects Ensure that all projects are delivered on-time, within scope and within budget
- Developing project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.
- Ensure resource availability and allocation.
- Develop a detailed project plan to track progress.
- Use appropriate verification techniques to manage changes in project scope, schedule and costs.
- Report and escalate to management as needed.
- Manage the relationship with the client and all stakeholders.
- Perform risk management to minimize project risks Establish and maintain relationships with third parties/vendors.
- Create and maintain comprehensive project documentation.

Markup Designs Pvt. Ltd IT *Project Manager*

Noida, UP

September 2019 - February 2020

- Coordinate internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of projects Ensure that all projects are delivered on-time, within scope and within budget
- Developing project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.
- Ensure resource availability and allocation.
- Develop a detailed project plan to track progress.
- Use appropriate verification techniques to manage changes in project scope, schedule and costs.
- Report and escalate to management as needed.
- Manage the relationship with the client and all stakeholders.
- Perform risk management to minimize project risks Establish and maintain relationships with third parties/vendors.
- Create and maintain comprehensive project documentation.

EGlogics Softech Pvt. Ltd IT Project Manager

Noida, UP

November 2018 - September 2019

- Track project performance, specifically to analyze the successful completion of short and long-term goals
- Meet budgetary objectives and make adjustments to project constraints based on financial analysis
- Develop comprehensive project plans to be shared with clients as well as other staff members
- Coordinate internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of projects.
- Ensure that all projects are delivered on-time, within scope and within budget.
- Assistant in the definition of project scope and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility
- Ensure resource availability and allocation
- Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress

- Manage changes to the project scope, project schedule and project costs using appropriate verification techniques.
- Measure project performance using appropriate tools and techniques
- Report and escalate to management as needed
- Manage the relationship with the client and all stakeholders
- Perform risk management to minimize project risks.
- Establish and maintain relationships with third parties/vendors.
- Create and maintain comprehensive project documentation
- Meet with clients to take detailed ordering briefs and clarify specific requirements of each project.

IMMIX Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Ghaziabad, UP

Project Coordinator

December 2012 - November 2018

- Ensuring that relevant management information is captured and analyzed.
- Assigning tasks & Control schedule.
- Working with the team to remove blockers
- Track, analyze and communicate project risks and opportunities.
- Involved in Coordinating projects from inception to completion.
- Keeping in close contact with key project members and decision makers
- Track and report project progress
- Update documentation
- Coordinated with clients to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Make sure that strategy, goals and objectives are stated
- Translate project objectives into tasks
- Create and maintain documentation
- Participate in performance review

RECOM InfoTech Pvt. Ltd

Ghaziabad, UP

Trainee

January 2012 - November 2012

- Join this organization as a "Trainee".
- Learn HTML, CSS, CORE PHP, WORDPRESS.
- Developed some Projects
- HTML conversion
- Wordpress Integration

Education

- MCA from UPTU University with 71.9%
- BCA from CCS University with 66.83%
- HSC from CBSE Board with 64.8%
- SSC from CBSE Board with 49.6%

Personal Details

Date of Birth : 27 April 1989
Marital status : Married
Languages known : Hindi and English.
Address : 7/57 Sector- 5 Rajendar Nagar, sahibabad Ghaziabad UP